



sainumechpd@gmail.com



Portfolio Website

Dribble

Bē Behance

in LinkedIn

ABOUT ME

As a Lead UX/UI designer, I bring extensive experience in designing for B2B, B2C, ERP mobile, and web applications. Coupled with a Master's degree in product design from Coventry University, United Kingdom, I am proud to have received 4 UX/UI Design awards from 3 reputed Fortune 500 companies.

EXPERIENCE

User Experience Lead

Aug 2022 - Present

Optum Global Solutions International B.V., Bengaluru

Senior UX Designer

Aug 2019 - Aug 2022

Yokogawa IA Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru

Senior UX Designer

Sep 2017 - Aug 2019

Prime Focus Technologies, Bengaluru

Product Designer

Nov 2014 - Feb 2017

Invntree Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

Product Designer

Jan 2009 - Aug 2012

Luk India Pvt. Ltd, Hosur

EDUCATION

M.sc in Product Design

2012 - 2014

Coventry University United Kingdom - Regular

 Master Degree in Product Design covered areas such as usercentered design, Design management, Design Innovation, and Design technology.

M.B.A in Production Managment

2010 - 2012

Indian School of Business Management - Distance

Diploma in Tool and die Engineering

2005 - 2008

Government polytechnic college, Thrissur, Kerala-Regular

AWARDS

UX Design Award - Consumer Centric 2023 Optum - United Health group, Bengaluru

UX Design Award - Perfomance 2023

Optum - United Health group, Bengaluru

Impact Award Project Support 2021

Yokogawa IA Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru

2018 **Design Award**

Prime Focus Technologies, Bengaluru

Public Speaker & Trainer Award 2019 & 2020

- Toast Master International
- Junior Chamber International

UX CERTIFICATION

Design Thinking

2019- Distinction Interaction Design Foundation Denmark

Google UX Design Professional Certificate

2019- Distinction

Google

SKILLS

- Product Design
- User Experience Design
- Personas, Scenarios & IA
- Mobile, Web & ERP Design
- User Research
- Usability Testing
- Wireframe
- Visual Design & Prototyping
- Building a strong design system and Assets with UI standards
- Generating a strong mood board based on the data analysis
- Manage Team and work very closely with Stakeholders, Users, Designers, and Developers from Project Kick off to UX sign-
- Stake holder interview, Competitor analysis, Data analysis and qualitative reviews from user research

TOOLS

- Figma
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Sketch
- Invision
- Zeplin

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Kannada
- Tamil
- Malayalam
- Urudu